G SHOBAN RAJ

Contact: (M) 91 - 9655441529

Email ID: shobanganesh22@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am seeking a competitive and challenging environment where I can serve your organization and establish a career myself.

Profile Summary:

Banking Professional with 3 years and 7 months experience in Banking Backend Operations. I have wide range of skills in Loan Processing, Funding, Insurance, Payment's Processing and lots of knowledge in the Retail Banking Operations.

Core Competencies:

- Ledger balancing Know your customer Loans
- Claims and Insurance US Mortgage loans
 Regulatory Compliance
- International Banking Insolvency and Bankruptcy Transactions

Applications:

• Respond Version 10.8.0 • Fullserve • Edocs documents view • Encompass

Work History:

Digital Interactive Solutions Private limited – Payroll of Digi Interactive Solutions Process Analyst Feb 2021 – Till date

- I am working in US Mortgage Loan processing team, Here we are reviewing the different types of loans.
- Documents received from the borrower regarding their mortgage loan process.
- We have looked at borrower eligibility of getting the loans and previous loans payment history.
- We are dealing with FHA, VA and USDA and Conventional loans.
- Using different applications to audit the loans.
- We have also check the AUS and DU underwriting report for the Loan amount, Monthly payment and Interest and Income.
- Supporting the Government Insuring process.

Barclays Global Services Centre Private Limited – Payroll of Kelly Services India Private Limited

Process Associate Dec 2017 - Nov 2020

- Handling BAU activities and support to Managers as well as Process Expert for testing project.
- Know Your Customer (KYC) checks is the basic criteria we have done for all the customers.
- Using Specific Banking Applications and Specific Calculators for the processing the complaint.
- Payments Claiming Process dealing with Loans, Overdraft, Mortgage accounts.
- Handled specialist complaints from Financial Ombudsman Service (FOS).
- Worked on Payment Break Plan new process migrated from onshore.
- Supported Quality check analysis team.
- Personal Customer and Business Customer Identification confirmed using internal evidence documents, National Identities, Customer Gateway Application, Royal mail Postcode finder link and Insolvency website link.

Matrix Business Services India Pvt Ltd

Client Executive

May 2016 - Oct 2017

- Background Verification process.
- Closely work with HR team members in the other reputed Organization's.
- Client support and relationship.
- Candidates follow-up's task.
- Update the reports status to client through E-mail and Calls.
- Reports checking and Initiation through client application portal.
- Pushing operations team to get the reports on time.

Education:

- Bachelor of Computer Science from Vel Tech RS Arts College (Madras University) during 2013-2016.
- Completed 12th Maths and Computer Science from (State Board) during 2011-2013 Government Higher Secondary School, Redhills, Chennai.
- Completed 10th (State Board) on 2011 from Government Higher Secondary School, Redhills, Chennai.

Personal Details:

Date of Birth - 30th July 1995

Present Address - 1/2488, Madha Temple Street, Sivanthi Athithan Nagar,

Gandhi Nagar, Redhills.

Chennai – 600052, Tamil Nadu, India

Languages known - English, Tamil (Read, Write)

Place:	YOURS FAITHFULLY,
Date:	